Myrta and Emory Ross Collection of African Photographs
Myrta and Emory Ross Collection of African Photographs
1897-1938
Ross, Emory.
2 linear ft.
Missionaries and friends of Albert Schweitzer. Photographs.
2581780
Biographical History
Emory Ross (1887-1973) was a missionary with the Disciples of Christ. He and his wife, Myrta, became friends with Albert Schweitzer while serving as missionaries in equatorial Africa, and were early supporters of the Albert Schweitzer Fellowship during World War II.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Myrta and Emory Ross Collection of African Photographs consists entirely of photographs of African people and places.
Arrangement of the Collection
Photographs are arranged alphabetically in each box by topic.
Related Material
See also the
Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Photography; Ross, Emory.; Ross, Myrta.; Africa -- Photographs.; Belgian Congo -- Photographs.; Liberia -- Photographs.; Nigeria -- Photographs.; Southern Rhodesia -- Photographs.; Photographs.; Filmstrips.; Missionaries.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Estelle Linzer
Inventory
- Filmstrips
  - Tumbra of Africa, with printed guide (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Congo, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Early Congo mission, 1897-1906 (Box 1)
  - Old Congo, 1928; 1938 (Box 1)
  - African faces (Box 2)
  - Congo life, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Congo Methodist mission (Box 2)
  - Early Congo mission (Box 2)
  - Joseph Clark's prints, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
  - Liberia, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Nigeria, Southern Rhodesia, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Southern Rhodesia, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Ubangi River, Congo, 1916? (Box 2)
  - West African coast, 1938 (Box 2)